[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Youth, dreams, dreams in life,
tuổi trẻ ước mơ ước mơ trong cuộc đời
creating in life so many lofty ideals so that the vast
tạo lập trong cuộc sống bao lý tưởng cao
world resounds with
vời để thế giới bao la vang lừng tiếng
praise, that is my youthful yearning.
ngợi ca là khát khao khát khao của tôi
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
The victory, not defeated, for walking through
vị chiến thắng không bại vì bước đi trên
life without leaving a trace, victory in the midst of the
đời không dấu tích chiến thắng ở giữa
vast stream, renouncing worldly life to stand on the
dòng mênh mông xuất gia để từ đứng phận
stone,
đá
meditating in the ancient forest, visiting
Thiền Định thiền định chốn rừng già từ
love, wandering from when?
vào thăm ái Du từ bao giờ
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Strong will, enlightenment, the impermanence of existence, attaining the
ý chí kiên cường giác ngộ lý vô thường
Dharma.
chứng Đà pháp
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
[Applause]
[Vỗ tay]
Youth, dreams, dreams in life,
tuổi trẻ ước mơ ước mơ trong cuộc đời
creating in life so many lofty ideals so that the vast
tao lập trong cuộc sống bao lý tướng Cao
world resounds with
Vời để thế giới bao la vang lần tia ngợi
praise, that is the yearning of so many young people.
ca là khát khao có bao người tuổi trẻ
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
For victory, not for me, walking through
vì chiến thắng không phải vì tôi đi trên
life without leaving a trace, falling into the
đời không dấu tích trên thân vật rơi
vast expanse, renouncing worldly life, from where? Buddha's Birthday,
rộng mênh mông xuất gia để từ đâu Phật
meditating in the ancient forest,
Đản thiền định thiền định chốn rừng già
from one day, love lulls, from sadness, to who, though yearning,
từ một hôm ái ru từ buồn làm Ai dù khát
yearning, the fox of
khao khát khao
impermanence, the Dharma.
hồ ly vô thường trường Đà pháp
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
That aspiration, I seek happiness in all
Khát Vọng ấy tôi ngược hạnh phúc khắp
ten directions.
mười phương
Young girls are becoming nuns, mostly female disciples,
tuổi trẻ con đang xuất gia làm đệ tử nữ
perhaps erasing the green background of the noble aspiration.
phần chừng đã xóa phông xanh Khát Vọng
That aspiration... I am often happy in all
khát vọng ấy Tôi thường hạnh phúc khắp
ten directions. That aspiration... I cherish happiness,
mười phương Khát Vọng ấy tôi thương hạnh
happiness, not happiness.
phúc không hạnh phúc
[music]
[âm nhạc]